Register of the Georgie Anne Geyer Papers, 1944-1996
Hoover Institution Archives
Georgie Anne Geyer papers,
1944-1996
91037
Geyer, Georgie Anne, 1935-
25 manuscript boxes, 9 card file boxes, 3 envelopes (13.9 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, notes, printed matter, and other research material, relating to President Fidel Castro of Cuba; Central America; and citizenship and immigration issues in the United States. Used in preparation of the books by G. A. Geyer, Guerrilla Prince: The Untold Story of Fidel Castro (Boston, 1991), and Americans No More: The Death of Citizenship (New York, 1996). Includes sound recordings and transcripts of interviews with a wide range of persons acquainted with Fidel Castro in a variety of capacities and at various periods of his life
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Castro, Fidel, 1927-; Cuba--History--1959-; Cuba; Central America; United States--Emigration and immigration; Citizenship--United States; United States--Politics and government; Phonotapes
Biography
1935, April 2 Born, Chicago, Illinois
1959-1975 Reporter, Chicago Daily News
1970 Author, The New Latins
1972 Author, The New Hundred Years War
1975-1980 Columnist, Los Angeles Times Syndicate
1976 Author, The Young Russians
1980- Columnist, Universal Press Syndicate
1983 Author, Buying the Night Flight
1991 Author, Guerilla Prince
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, notes, printed matter, and other research material, relating to President Fidel Castro of Cuba; Central America; and citizenship and immigration issues in the United States. Used in preparation of the books by G. A. Geyer, Guerrilla Prince: The Untold Story of Fidel Castro (Boston, 1991), and Americans No More: The Death of Citizenship (New York, 1996). Includes sound recordings and transcripts of interviews with a wide range of persons acquainted with Fidel Castro in a variety of capacities and at various periods of his life.
Container List
- Biographical File, 1967-1968 (Box 1.)
  Clipping and Memoranda. Arranged chronologically
  - Clipping and memoranda (Box 1., Folder 1)
- Speeches and Writings, 1966-1991 (Box 1.-6.)
  Drafts and printed copies of writings by Georgie Anne Geyer, with related correspondence, clippings, and miscellany. Arranged chronologically
  - "Cubans Still Latin," Washington Post, 1966 September 5. Printed copy (Box 1., Folder 2)
  - "U.S. Role Grows in Guatemala Rebel Threat," Washington Post, 1966 December 13. Printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "The Debray Case," Chicago Daily News, 1967 August. Printed copy (incomplete) and notes (Folder 4)
  - "A U.S. Diplomatic Bumble?" Christian Science Monitor, 1967 January 19. Printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "Why Guevara Failed," Saturday Review, 1968 August 24 (Folder 6)
  - "The CIA's Hired Killers," True for Today's Man, 1970 February. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Tearing Up Chile," New Republic, 1970 August 29. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Cuba: School for U.S. Radicals," Chicago Daily News, 1970 October 12. Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "Cuba's Influence Seen in U.S. Bomb Wave," Los Angeles Times, 1970 October 13. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "'We Threw Bombs... and the Whole Society Stopped,'" Los Angeles Times, 1970 October 14. Printed copy (Folder 11)
  - "Cuba's U.N. Mission a Center for Radicals," Los Angeles Times, 1970 October 15. Printed copy (Folder 12)
  - "Fidel 'Father' to Radicals," Chicago Daily News, 1970 October 15. Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - "Cuba's Fields: Harvest of Violence," Chicago Daily News, 1970 October 17. Printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "The Odyssey of a Black Militant," Chicago Daily News, 1970 October 20. Printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "Havana is Russia's 'Window' to U.S. Militants," Chicago Daily News, 1970 October 22. Printed copy (Folder 16)
  - "Unrest Cooling Off?" Chicago Daily News, 1970 October 24. Printed copy (Folder 17)
  - Review of K. S. Karol, Guerrillas in Power: The Course of the Cuban Revolution, Saturday Review, 1971 March 6. Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Hugger-Mugger in the Andes," Chicago Daily News (?), 1971 May 3. Printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "Reporter Tricked, Held 3 Hours by Guerrillas," Los Angeles Times, 1973 April 14. Printed copy (Folder 20)
  - "Castro Sinks His Knife into the Social Fabric of the U.S.," Chicago Sun Times, 1984 June 5. Printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Georgie Anne Geyer: 'Musolini fue el heroe de la juventud de Fidel,'" La Voz de Galicia, 1985 July 27. Printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "Fidel's Fickle Way with Spain," Washington Times, 1985 August 5. Printed copy (Folder 23)
  - "Tracing Castro's Roots in Brooding Galicia," Washington Times, 1985 August 12. Printed copy (Folder 24)
  - "Fidel (Almost) Gets Religion," 1985 December 3. Printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Fidel, the Lion, and the Lamb," 1985 December 4. Printed copy (Folder 26)
  - "From the Bay of Pigs Arcana," Washington Times, 1986 April 23. Printed copy (Folder 27)
  - "Who is Fidel Castro?" Currents in Modern Thought, 1990 May. Proofs (Folder 28)
  - Guerrilla Prince, 1991
    - General
      - Miscellany. Lists, photograph reproduction requests, and letter by George Bush, 1986-1991 (Folder 29)
      - Reviews, 1991 (Folder 30)
    - First drafts
      - Prologue-Chapter 8 (Folder 31-39)
      - Chapters 9-20 (Box 2., Folder 1-12)
      - Chapters 21-31 (Box 3., Folder 1-11)
    - Second draft (Box 4.)
      - Preamble-Chapter 18 (Folder 1-19)
      - Chapters 19-31 (Box 5., Folder 1-12)
    - Final draft
      - Prologue-Chapter 6 (Folder 13-19)
      - Chapters 7-26 (Box 6., Folder 1-20)
  - "Basking in the Reader's Limelight," 1991 Summer. Printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Fidel and Franco: The Ultimate Odd Couple," 1991 July 12. Printed copy (Folder 22)
- Interviews and Sources for Guerrilla Prince, 1984-1989 (Box 7.-13.)
  Typescript interview notes and transcripts, printed copies and related material including clippings, writings, and speeches. Arranged alphabetically by interviewee
  - General (Box 7.)
    - Lists, 1986-1988 (Folder 1)
    - Notes, 1985-1988 (Folder 2)
  - Anonymous and unidentified, 1985-1987 (Folder 3)
  - Aall, Sally, 1987 (Folder 4)
  - Abascal, Gerardo, 1985 (Folder 5)
  - Abourezk, James, 1985 (Folder 6)
  - Ache, Josefina, 1986 (Folder 7)
  - Agramonte, Roberto, 1985 (Folder 8)
  - Aguilar, Juan, 1984 (Folder 9)
  - Aguilar, Luis E., 1985 (Folder 10)
  - Aldrich, Frank, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - Alexander, William V., Jr., 1985. Includes clipping (Folder 12)
  - Alonzo, Jose, 1986 (Folder 13)
  - Amador, Fausto, 1987 (Folder 14)
  - Amador, Rolando, 1986-1987 (Folder 15)
  - Andersen, William, 1987 (Folder 16)
  - Anderson, Jack, 1989 (Folder 17)
  - Arcocha, Juan, 1985 (Folder 18)
  - Arias, Inocencio, 1986 (Folder 19)
  - Armas, Hector de, 1985 (Folder 20)
  - Arques, Manuel, 1986 (Folder 21)
  - Arroyo, Nicolas and Rafael Miquel, 1985 (Folder 22)
  - Asencio, Lazaro, 1987 (Folder 23)
  - Aspillaga, Florentino, 1988. Includes clipping (Folder 24)
  - Balart, Waldo, 1985 (Folder 25)
  - Baldizon Aviles, Jose, 1985 (Folder 26)
  - Balladares, Walter and Mario Torres, 1985 (Folder 27)
  - Banks, Richard, 1986 (Folder 28)
  - Barquin, Ramon, 1985 (Folder 29)
  - Bastillo, Carlos, 1985 (Folder 30)
  - Bayo, Alberto, Jr., 1986 (Folder 31)
  - Belli, Humberto, 1987 (Folder 32)
  - Belt, Guillermo and Mrs. Belt, 1987 (Folder 33)
  - Benemelis, Juan, 1985 (Folder 34)
  - Benes, Bernardo, 1985-1986 (Folder 35)
  - Bernard, Hector, 1986 (Folder 36)
  - Beruff, Jorge, 1984-1985 (Folder 37)
  - Besom, Don, 1986 (Folder 38)
  - Betancourt, Ernesto, 1984 (Folder 39)
  - Betancourt, Raquel, 1985 (Folder 40)
  - Blight, Jim, n.d. (Folder 41)
  - Bonilla Sosa, Victor, 1985 (Folder 42)
  - Borrell Navarro, Eduardo, 1986 (Folder 43)
  - Bosch, Juan, 1986 (Folder 44)
  - Bosch, Pepin, 1985 (Folder 45)
  - Bourgin, Marieda, 1985 (Folder 46)
  - Caballero, Danilo, 1985 (Folder 47)
  - Caballero, Emilio C., 1986 (Folder 48)
  - Cabrera, Lydia, n.d. (Folder 49)
  - Camella, Maria, 1985 (Folder 50)
  - Campuzano, Otilio, 1986 (Folder 51)
  - Canet, Gerardo, 1985 (Folder 52)
  - Cantell, Karl, 1988 (Folder 53)
  - Cardenas, Orlando de, 1985-1986 (Folder 54)
  - Carrillo, Justo, 1985-1986 (Folder 55)
  - Carrillo, Santiago, 1985 (Folder 56)
  - Casals, Hamlet, 1986 (Box 8., Folder 1)
  - Castaneda, Carlos, 1985 (Folder 2)
  - Castro, Alberto de, 1986 (Folder 3)
  - Castro, Fidel, 1984-1988 (Folder 4)
  - Cerda, Jose de la, 1985 (Folder 5)
  - Chamon, Arturo, 1986 (Folder 6)
  - Chayet, Zack, 1984 (Folder 7)
  - Chibas, Raul, 1985 (Folder 8)
  - Church, Bethine (Mrs. Frank Church), 1985 (Folder 9)
  - Cisneros, Rogelio, 1986 (Folder 10)
  - Cleaver, Eldridge, 1984 (Folder 11)
  - Clews, Enrique, 1986-1987 (Folder 12)
  - Colby, William, 1987 (Folder 13)
  - Cole, Lester, 1985 (Folder 14)
  - Conde, Francisco, 1985 (Folder 15)
  - Conte Aguero, Luis, 1986 (Folder 16)
  - Cordoba Claure, Teddy, 1986 (Folder 17)
  - Correa, Mayin, 1985 (Folder 18)
  - Costa, Octavio, 1984 (Folder 19)
  - Crosby, Ken and Clarence Moore, 1987 (Folder 20)
  - Cubela, Rolando, 1985. Includes related material (Folder 21)
  - Custodio, Alvaro, 1986 (Folder 22)
  - Custodio, Isabel, n.d. (Folder 23)
  - Dacosta Fernandes, Tony, 1989 (Folder 24)
  - Dalmau, Alberto, 1985 (Folder 25)
  - Dario Rumbat, Ruben, 1985 (Folder 26)
  - David, Henry P., 1986. Includes related material (Folder 27)
  - Diaz Balart, Frank, 1985 (Folder 28)
  - Diaz Balart, Rafael, 1984-1985. Includes related material (Folder 29)
  - Diaz Balart, Waldo, 1985 (Folder 30)
  - Diaz Francisco, Angel, 1985 (Folder 31)
  - Diaz, Lomberto, 1985 (Folder 32)
  - Dorta Duque, Juan Manuel, 1985-1986 (Folder 33)
  - Draper, Theodore, 1986 (Folder 34)
  - Echerri, Vicente, 1986 (Folder 35)
  - Enders, Thomas, 1985 (Folder 36)
  - Escalona, Hilda Felipe de, 1987 (Folder 37)
  - Esquivel, Alfredo, 1986 (Folder 38)
  - Facio, Gonzalo, 1985 (Folder 39)
  - Falcon Briceno, Marcos, 1986 (Folder 40)
  - Farach, Antonio, 1984. Includes related material (Folder 41)
  - Feal, Marcelino and Teresa, 1984-1987 (Folder 42)
  - Fernandez, Conchita, 1985 (Folder 43)
  - Fernandez, Jose Ramon, 1985 (Box 9., Folder 1-3)
  - Figueiredo, Paulo, 1985 (Folder 4)
  - Figueres, Jose, 1985 (Folder 5)
  - Figuero, Julio, 1984 (Folder 6)
  - Fleites, Armando, 1985 (Folder 7)
  - Flores, Edmundo, 1986 (Folder 8)
  - Fouad, Hamdi, 1986 (Folder 9)
  - Francis, Sandra Hodgkins, 1985-1986 (Folder 10)
  - Franqui, Carlos, 1985 (Folder 11)
  - Frayde, Martha, 1985 (Folder 12)
  - Fuentes, Norberto, 1985 (Folder 13)
  - Gaitan, Gloria, 1986 (Folder 14)
  - Galis Menendez, Armando, 1987 (Folder 15)
  - Garcia, Euripides and Rina, 1985 (Folder 16)
  - Garcia, Orlando, 1986 (Folder 17)
  - Garcia Meras, Emilio, 1986 (Folder 18)
  - Gefter, Saul S., 1985 (Folder 19)
  - George, Alexander L., 1987 (Folder 20)
  - Giandoni, William, 1984 (Folder 21)
  - Gillespie, Tony, 1986 (Folder 22)
  - Ginjauma, Jose de Jesus, 1986 (Folder 23)
  - Giorgis, Dawit Wolde, 1986 (Folder 24)
  - Goethals, Henry, 1985 (Folder 25)
  - Goheen, Robert, 1987 (Folder 26)
  - Gomez, Cesar, 1986 (Folder 27)
  - Gonzalez, Ed, 1984 (Folder 28)
  - Gonzalez Jerez, Raul, 1987 (Folder 29)
  - Gonzalez Lopez, Emilio, 1986 (Folder 30)
  - Gonzalez Regueral, Jose Ramon, 1985 (Folder 31)
  - Gordon, Barbara, 1985 (Folder 32)
  - Grobart, Fabio, 1985 (Folder 33-34)
  - Gross, Narciso, 1986 (Box 10., Folder 1)
  - Guede, Emilio, 1985 (Folder 2)
  - Guevara, Alfredo, 1985 (Folder 3-4)
  - Hakser, P. N., 1986 (Folder 5)
  - Halperin, Maurice, 1986 (Folder 6)
  - Hart Davalos, Armando, 1985 (Folder 7)
  - Heredia, Richard, 1987 (Folder 8)
  - Hernandez, Francisco, 1986 (Folder 9)
  - Hernandez, Melba, 1985 (Folder 10)
  - Hernandez Garcia, Salvador, 1986. Includes related material (Folder 11)
  - Herrera, Maria Cristina, 1986 (Folder 12)
  - Hodgkins, Don, 1986 (Folder 13)
  - Hollander, Paul, 1986 (Folder 14)
  - Horowitz, Leonard, 1986 (Folder 15)
  - Hurtado, Fernando and Enrique Ovares, 1987 (Folder 16)
  - Hussain, Labarok, 1986 (Folder 17)
  - Ihsan Abdul Kuddous, 1986 (Folder 18)
  - Izquierda, Jose Maria, 1985 (Folder 19)
  - Jackson, Jesse, 1985 (Folder 20)
  - Jenkins, Brian, 1984 (Folder 21)
  - Jimenez Leal, Orlando, 1986. Includes related material (Folder 22)
  - Jordan, Robert Francis, 1987 (Folder 23)
  - Kannaouros, Andres, 1986 (Folder 24)
  - Kaul, T. N., 1986 (Folder 25)
  - Keegan, Pat, 1985 (Folder 26)
  - Kelly, Ken, 1987 (Folder 27)
  - Khisha, M., 1986 (Folder 28)
  - Kopilow, David J., 1984 (Folder 29)
  - Kucharski, Taddeausz, 1986 (Folder 30)
  - Lacey, Robert, 1988 (Folder 31)
  - Larroque, Enrique, 1985 (Folder 32)
  - Lasorda, Tommy, 1986 (Folder 33)
  - Lazarus, Wilfred, 1986 (Folder 34)
  - Lebredo, Luis and Angel Aparicio Laurencio, 1986 (Folder 35)
  - Leland, Mickey, 1985 (Folder 36)
  - Lenay, Susan, 1985 (Folder 37)
  - Leogrand, Bill, 1986 (Folder 38)
  - Leonhardy, Terrance, 1986 (Folder 39)
  - Lesnick, Max, 1984 (Folder 40)
  - Levy, Nick, 1986 (Folder 41)
  - Lew, Salvador, 1987 (Folder 42)
  - Lima, Facundo, 1985-1989 (Folder 43)
  - Llaca, Enrique, 1986 (Box 11., Folder 1)
  - Lleras Restrepo, Carlos, 1986 (Folder 2)
  - Llerena, Mario, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Llorente, Armando, 1985 (Folder 4)
  - Llovio, Jose Luis, 1987 (Folder 5)
  - Lopez Castro, Esther, 1986 (Folder 6)
  - Lopez Michelsen, Alfonso, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - Lora, Armando, 1985 (Folder 8)
  - Lord, Marjorie, 1985 (Folder 9)
  - Lufti al Kholi, 1986 (Folder 10)
  - Lyssarides, Dr., 1986 (Folder 11)
  - McClendon, Sarah, 1986 (Folder 12)
  - McGovern, George, 1985 (Folder 13)
  - Malone, James, 1985 (Folder 14)
  - Manet, Eduardo and Ramon Suarez, 1985 (Folder 15)
  - Manley, Michael, 1986 (Folder 16)
  - Martin, Dolores, 1985 (Folder 17)
  - Martinez, Alice, 1987 (Folder 18)
  - Martinez Corbala, Gonzalo, 1986 (Folder 19)
  - Martinez Ferrer, Richard, 1985 (Folder 20)
  - Martinez Marques, Guillermo, 1986 (Folder 21)
  - Masferrer, Raymundo, 1986 (Folder 22)
  - Matos, Huber, 1985-1986 (Folder 23)
  - Matos, Huber, Jr., 1985-1987 (Folder 24)
  - Medrano, Humberto, 1984 (Folder 25)
  - Meguid, Mr., 1986 (Folder 26)
  - Mendenez, Rosa, 1985 (Folder 27)
  - Mendoza, Jorge Enrique, circa 1985 (Folder 28)
  - Mestre, Ramon, 1985. Includes related material (Folder 29)
  - Meyer, Karl, 1985 (Folder 30)
  - Meza, Victor, 1986 (Folder 31)
  - Migdail, Carl, 1985 (Folder 32)
  - Mikoyan, Sergo, 1988 (Folder 33)
  - Miquez, Alberto, 1985 (Folder 34)
  - Miranda, Roger, 1988 (Folder 35)
  - Miret Prieto, Pedro, 1985 (Folder 36-37)
  - Mitrani, David, 1986 (Folder 38)
  - Monserrat, Rene, 1985 (Folder 39)
  - Montaner, Carlos Alberto, 1984-1986 (Folder 40)
  - Montenegro, Alejandro, 1984 (Folder 41)
  - Moore, Clarence, 1985 (Folder 42)
  - Mora, Manuel, 1985 (Folder 43)
  - Mora, Victor, n.d. (Folder 44)
  - Morales, Carlos, 1986 (Folder 45)
  - Moran, Mark, 1987 (Folder 46)
  - Mori, Oscar, n.d. (Folder 47)
  - Munroe, Trevor, n.d. (Folder 48)
  - Nashishibi, Nasir, 1985 (Folder 49)
  - Navarro, Antonio, 1985 (Folder 50)
  - Navarro, Pepe, 1985 (Folder 51)
  - Negretti, Luis, 1986 (Folder 52)
  - Nettleford, Rex, 1986 (Box 12., Folder 1)
  - Ngueve, Pedro, 1987 (Folder 2)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1987 (Folder 3)
  - Nunez Jimenez, Antonio, 1985 (Folder 4)
  - Obando y Bravo, Miguel, 1986 (Folder 5)
  - Ochoa, Emilio, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Oranges, Alfredo, 1985 (Folder 7)
  - Orlani, Antonio, 1985 (Folder 8)
  - Ortega, Luis, 1987 (Folder 9)
  - Pais, Agustin, 1986 (Folder 10)
  - Palmer, John, 1987 (Folder 11)
  - Pardo Llada, Jose, 1986 (Folder 12)
  - Pastora, Eden, 1986 (Folder 13)
  - Pazos, Felipe, 1986 (Folder 14)
  - Pazos, Javier and Orlando Castro, 1986 (Folder 15)
  - Pena Gomez, Jose Francisco, 1986 (Folder 16)
  - Perez, Faustino, 1985 (Folder 17)
  - Perez Alamo, Dunny, 1987 (Folder 18)
  - Perez Cott, Gustavo. Radio Marti broadcast, n.d. (Folder 19)
  - Perez Lopez, Jorge, 1986 (Folder 20)
  - Perez Puelles, Gerardo, 1986 (Folder 21)
  - Perez Sanchez, Manuel Antonio, 1986 (Folder 22)
  - Phillips, David, 1986-1987 (Folder 23)
  - Pino, Angel, 1987 (Folder 24)
  - Pino, Mario J., 1986 (Folder 25)
  - Pino, Rafael del, 1987 (Folder 26)
  - Portell Vila, Herminio, 1986 (Folder 27)
  - Prado, Gary, 1987 (Folder 28)
  - Rakowski, Mieczyslaw, 1985 (Folder 29)
  - Rangel, Beatrice, 1986 (Folder 30)
  - Rangel, Carlos Alberto, 1986 (Folder 31)
  - Rasco, Jose Ignacio, 1985 (Folder 32)
  - Rasgotra, Maharajkrishna, 1986 (Folder 33)
  - Ratliff, William, 1986 (Folder 34)
  - Ray, Manuel, 1985 (Folder 35)
  - Regalado, Tomas, 1984-1985 (Folder 36)
  - Reston, Tom, 1986 (Folder 37)
  - Richardson, Edgerton, 1986 (Folder 38)
  - Rivero Aguero, Andres, 1985 (Folder 39)
  - Roberto, Holden, 1986 (Folder 40)
  - Roca Calderio, Blas, 1985 (Folder 41)
  - Rodriguez, Carlos Rafael, 1985 (Folder 42)
  - Rodriguez, Conrad, 1986 (Folder 43)
  - Rodriguez, Pepin and Manolo, 1985-1987 (Folder 44)
  - Romero, Napoleon, 1986 (Folder 45)
  - Roque Leon, Jose, 1985 (Folder 46)
  - Rosa Coutinho, Antonio, 1988 (Folder 47)
  - Roy, Sunil Kumar, 1986 (Folder 48)
  - Rubottom, Roy, 1986. Includes clipping (Box 13., Folder 1)
  - Saballos, Angela, 1986 (Folder 2)
  - Sabo, Ann, 1986 (Folder 3)
  - Sahnoun, Mohamed, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Samper, Maria Elena, 1986 (Folder 5)
  - Sanchez Durante, Universo, 1985 (Folder 6)
  - Sanchez Perez, Alberto, 1986 (Folder 7)
  - Sanchez Perez, Manuel, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Sanguinetti, Jorge, 1986 (Folder 9)
  - Santos Calderon, Enrique, 1986 (Folder 10)
  - Santos Castillo, Enrique, 1986 (Folder 11)
  - Sargen, Andres Nazario, 1985 (Folder 12)
  - Sargento Jese, Jesus de Martinez, 1985 (Folder 13)
  - Savimbi, Jonas, 1986-1988 (Folder 14)
  - Schofield, Virginia, 1986 (Folder 15)
  - Seaga, Edward, 1986 (Folder 16)
  - Shackley, Theodore, 1986-1989 (Folder 17)
  - Shevchenko, Arkady, 1987 (Folder 18)
  - Shultz, George, 1985 (Folder 19)
  - Silva, Victor, 1985 (Folder 20)
  - Skelly, Jack, 1984 (Folder 21)
  - Soler, Eugenio, 1986 (Folder 22)
  - Soni, Ambika, 1986 (Folder 23)
  - Sori Marin, Mariano, 1985 (Folder 24)
  - Sosa Family, 1986 (Folder 25)
  - Spaulding, Winston, 1986 (Folder 26)
  - Stephansky, Ben, 1986 (Folder 27)
  - Sterling, Marques, n.d. (Folder 28)
  - Suchlicki, Jaime, 1986 (Folder 29)
  - Szulc, Tad, 1987 (Folder 30)
  - Tamargo, Agustin, 1985 (Folder 31)
  - Tambs, Lewis, 1985 (Folder 32)
  - Tandon, Rajeshwari, 1986 (Folder 33)
  - Terzi, Zuhdi, 1987 (Folder 34)
  - Thomas, Hugh, 1985 (Folder 35)
  - Torrijos, Moises, 1985 (Folder 36)
  - Tourguy, Michel, n.d. (Folder 37)
  - Tourino, Santiago, 1985 (Folder 38)
  - Trueba, Enrique, 1984-1986 (Folder 39)
  - Valdes Menendez, Ramiro, 1985 (Folder 40)
  - Valencia Tovar, Alvaro, 1986 (Folder 41)
  - Valle, Blanca del, 1987 (Folder 42)
  - Valle Vallejo, Antonio Ricardo, 1988 (Folder 43)
  - Valls, Jorge, 1986-1987 (Folder 44)
  - Vargas Gomez, Andres, n.d. (Folder 45)
  - Varona, Tony, 1985 (Folder 46)
  - Vaughan, Jack, 1986 (Folder 47)
  - Vega, Jaime, 1985 (Folder 48)
  - Viera, Bernardo, 1986 (Folder 49)
  - Villar, Arturo, 1985 (Folder 50)
  - Wallace, Jim, 1985 (Folder 51)
  - Walte, Juan, 1986 (Folder 52)
  - Walter, Vernon, 1985 (Folder 53)
  - Warren, Curtis, 1987 (Folder 54)
  - Wiecha (Chapman), Robert, n.d. (Folder 55)
  - Zayas, Carlos, 1987 (Folder 56)
- Notes for Guerrilla Prince, 1944-1987 (Box 14.-16.)
  Transcript notes, and related material including correspondence, reports, and printed matter. Arranged numerically
  - 1. Childhood. Includes printed matter, n.d. (Box 14., Folder 1)
  - 2. Mother. Includes interview and clipping, 1986-1987 (Folder 2)
  - 3. Father (Folder 3)
  - 4. Sister Juana. Includes interview (Folder 4)
  - 5. Brothers (Folder 5)
  - 6. Raul. Includes a clipping, 1984 (Folder 6)
  - 7. Formation under Jesuits. Includes printed matter, 1944-1987 (Folder 7)
  - 8. Early fascination with fascism (Folder 8)
  - 9. Romance and marriage. Includes printed matter, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - 10. Women in his life - attitude toward. Includes clippings, letter by Dolores Martin, and printed excerpt, 1965-1987 (Folder 10)
  - 11. How he formed revolution (Folder 11)
  - 12. Mexican repatriation. Includes printed matter, 1957 (Folder 12)
  - 14. Moncada attack. Includes printed matter and a typescript by Antonio de la Coba (?), "The Attack in Bayamo," n.d. (Folder 13)
  - 15. Return to Sierra Maestra (Folder 14)
  - 16. Years in Sierra Maestra. Includes printed matter, 1957-1988 (Folder 15)
  - 17. Psychological analyses of Fidel (Folder 16)
  - 18. City directorate and other democrats. Includes news wire reports and printed list, n.d. (Folder 17)
  - 19 Marching into Havana (Folder 18)
  - 20. American Journalist in Sierra. Includes printed matter, 1967-1969 (Folder 19)
  - 22. The first year (Folder 20)
  - 23. How he became a Marxist (Box 15., Folder 1)
  - 24. The 1960s (Folder 2)
  - 25. The non-aligned movement. Includes printed matter, 1983 (Folder 3)
  - 27. Fascination with Africa (Folder 4)
  - 28. Move into Angola (Folder 5)
  - 29. Soviets take over economy. Includes printed matter, 1981 (Folder 6)
  - 30. Guerrilla failures in 1960s. Includes clippings, 1967-1969 (Folder 7)
  - 31. Relations with Latin America (Folder 8)
  - 32. Training guerrillas (Folder 9)
  - 33. Relations with Soviets. Includes typescript report, 1968 (Folder 10)
  - 34. Celia Sanchez. Includes printed matter, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - 35. Fidelito (son). Includes printed matter, 1979-1980 (Folder 12)
  - 42. Relations with Carter Administration (Folder 13)
  - 44. American visitors. Includes printed matter, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - 47. Huber Matos affair. Includes printed matter, 1959-1980 (Folder 15)
  - 48. Camilo affair. Includes clipping, 1985 (Folder 16)
  - 49. University years. Printed matter only, 1971 (Folder 17)
  - 50. Bogotazo. Includes printed matter and an interview with Fidel Castro, 1948-1983 (Folder 18)
  - 51. Why Cuba was different (Folder 19)
  - 52. Cuba today and future developments (Box 16., Folder 1)
  - 53. Che. Includes printed matter and correspondence by Antonio de la Cana, Liu Yu-Wan, and William Ratliff, 1960-1985 (Folder 2)
  - 54. Visit to Chile and Allende (Folder 3)
  - 55. Bay of Pigs. Includes printed matter, 1968-1986 (Folder 4)
  - 58. Missile crisis. Includes printed matter, 1962-1981 (Folder 5)
  - 59. Homosexuality (Folder 6)
  - 60. Internal organization of Cuba: Ideologicalization and how changed. Breaking with Fidel (Folder 7)
  - 64. Relations with Black Americans. Includes printed matter, 1967-1982 (Folder 8)
  - 65. Fidel Castro and Europe (Folder 9)
  - 66. Genetics and other quirks. Includes printed matter, 1984-1989 (Folder 10)
  - 67. Spain and Galicia. Includes printed matter, 1973-1985. SEE ALSO: INTERVIEWS/Cerda, Jose de la, Conde, Francisco and Gonzalez Lopez, Emilio (Folder 11)
  - 71. Jamaica (Folder 12)